你好，莱昂内尔，你好吗？
Hello Lionel, how are you doing?
Hola Lionel, ¿cómo te va?
就在你右边的后面。
-  -
你好吗？
Here behind to your right.
Acá detrás a tu derecha.
我们为蒂克斯体育直播。
How are you?
¿Cómo estás?
嗯，首先问你关于...
We are live for Tix Sports.
Estamos en vivo para Tix Sports.
在……发生之前，你是如何度过这一切的？
Well, first ask you about...
Bueno, primero preguntarte por...
决赛的推迟，显然是与卡塔尔的比赛的推迟，原因显而易见。
How did you live all this prior to what was...?
¿Cómo viviste toda esta previa a lo que fue...?
大家都在谈论一个想玩，另一个不想玩，每个人都在谈论。
the postponement of the very final and obviously the match with Qatar for obvious reasons.
la postergación de la finalísima y obviamente el partido con Qatar por cuestiones obvias.
我需要听听你对此的看法......
There was a lot of talk about one wanting to play, the other not, everyone talked.
que se habló mucho de que uno quiso jugar, el otro no, hablaron todos.
你如何看待这两场友谊赛，也许是对手实力较小的比赛？
I needed to hear your opinion about this...
faltaba escucharte a vos de tu opinión acerca de esta...
新的时间也许会得到更好的东西。
How do you take these two friendlies, perhaps with lesser rivals?
¿Cómo tomás estos dos amistosos, quizás con rivales menores?
嗯，大家下午好。
new time to maybe get something better.
nuevo tiempo para quizás conseguir algo mejor.
好吧，我们如何看待它。
Well, good afternoon everyone.
Bueno, buenas tardes para todos.
或多或少像你一样，我们遵循......
Well, how we take it.
Bueno, como lo tomamos.
消息来自...
More or less like you, we were following the...
Más o menos como ustedes, íbamos siguiendo la...
来自卡塔尔，事实是他们的想法不太有前瞻性。
the news that came from...
las noticias que venían desde...
随着时间的推移，我们开始说事情变得越来越复杂，我们必须寻找不同的替代方案。
from Qatar and the truth is that they were not very forward-thinking.
de Qatar y la verdad que no eran muy adelantadoras.
好吧，一切都被耽搁了。
Over time we began to say that it was getting complicated and that we had to look for different alternatives.
Con tiempo nosotros empezamos a decir que se estaba complicando y que había que buscar diferentes alternativas.
正如你所知，直到前周日为止发生了什么……
Well, everything was delayed.
Bueno, todo se retrasó.
在开始之前。
What happened, as you well know, until the Sunday before...
que pasó, como ustedes bien saben, hasta el día domingo antes de...
事实上，周一我们要去卡塔尔旅行。
In fact, on Monday we were going to travel to Qatar.
De hecho, nosotros el lunes íbamos a viajar a Qatar.
周日我们仍然不知道比赛在哪里进行。
and on Sunday we still didn't know where the game was being played.
y el domingo todavía no sabíamos dónde se jugaba.
我认为一切都被推迟了，我认为这不是任何人的错，因为有一个......
I think everything was delayed, I think it's no one's fault because there is a...
Creo que se retrasó todo, creo que no es culpa de nadie porque hay una...
这是部长没有见过的情况。
-  -
怎么样了？
A situation that the minister had not seen.
Una situación que el ministro no lo había visto.
好，好。
How's it going?
¿Cómo te va?
我没见过你。
Good, good.
Bien, bien.
这不是任何人的错，似乎足球是次要问题。
I hadn't seen you.
No te había visto.
从那时起，印刷量就开始疲软，那一周真是……
And that's no one's fault, it seems that football is a secondary issue.
Y eso no es culpa de nadie, parece que el fútbol está en un tema secundario.
很难，我们希望尽快解决，但没有达成一致。
From there a weak print run began and that week was quite...
A partir de ahí sí que empezó un tiraje floje y esa semana fue bastante...
但是比赛必须在二十七号在卡塔尔进行，这一点很明确，那就是，
difficult, we wanted it to be resolved as quickly as possible, an agreement was not reached.
difícil, nosotros queríamos que se resuelva lo más rápido posible, no se llegó a un acuerdo.
其他一切都是争论，没有多大意义。
but the game had to be played on the twenty-seventh in Qatar, that was very clear, that is,
pero que el partido se tenía que jugar el día veintisiete en Catar eso estaba clarísimo o sea que
也就是说，从那里我们开始寻找......
Everything else is a controversy that doesn't make much sense.
todo lo otro es una polémica que no tiene mucho sentido.
竞争对手，因为我们没有任何具体的东西，这表明这不是经过深思熟虑的事情。
That said, from there we started looking...
Dicho esto, nosotros a partir de ahí empezamos a buscar...
好吧，如果考虑到的话，也许我们会抛下一切，酒店并没有为我们来这里做好准备。
rivals because we didn't have anything concrete, that gives the indication that it was not something thought out.
rivales porque no teníamos nada concreto, eso da la pauta de que no fue algo pensado.
这就是已经发生的事情，超越了任何其他争议。
Well, if it had been thought about, maybe we would have left everything, the property was not prepared for us to come here.
Pues si hubiera sido pensado, a lo mejor, hubiéramos salido todo, el predio no estaba preparado para que nosotros vengamos acá.
好吧，最后我认为我们来到这里是积极的。
And this is what has happened, beyond any other controversy.
Y esto es lo que ha pasado, más allá de cualquier otra polémica.
男孩们来了，和他们的家人在一起，可以是自由的。
Well, at last I think it's positive for us to be here.
Bueno, al fin creo que para nosotros es positivo estar acá.
我们变得更好了，尤其是我们训练的新人，我们能够进行有趣的训练。
that the boys come, be with their family, can be free.
que los chicos vengan, estén con su familia, puedan estar libres.
最后我们必须积极地对待它，我认为这是非常积极的，最重要的是，我们已经
We got even better, especially the new guys we trained, we were able to do interesting training.
Nos colocamos aún más, sobre todo los chicos nuevos que entrenemos, pudimos hacer entrenamientos interesantes.
两场友谊赛，对手必须得到尊重。
Two friendly matches in which the rivals must be respected.
Dos partidos amistosos en los cuales los rivales hay que respetarlos.
这些是可以玩的游戏，可以看到我认为的男孩
and they are games to play and to see the boys who I think
y son partidos para jugar y para ver a los chicos que creo que
他们应该得到一个机会，他们应该赢得一个世界杯席位，或者至少为之奋斗。
They deserve an opportunity and they deserve to earn a place or at least fight for it for the World Cup.
Merecen una oportunidad y merecen porque no ganarse un sitio o por lo menos pelearlo para el Mundial.
下午好，Disport、Disport Radio 和 Dona María 的 Leónel Fernández 先生。
Good afternoon, Mr. Leónel Fernández, for Disport, Disport Radio and Dona María.
Buenas tardes, señor Leónel Fernández, para Disport, Disport Radio y Dona María.
随着接二连三的电话，我们总是问您...
With the succession of calls, we always ask you...
Con la sucesión de convocatorias, siempre te preguntamos...
你在最终名单中所占的比例是多少？
How much percentage do you have of the final list?
¿cuánto porcentaje tenés de la lista definitiva
为了世界杯。
for the world cup.
para el mundial.
这是你要奉献的最后一份，因为你的下一份奉献将是极限赛和世界杯的号召。
This was the last one you are going to give, because the next one you give is going to be with the limit and with the call for the World Cup.
Esta fue la última que vas a dar, porque la próxima que des ya va a ser con el límite y con la convocatoria para el mundial.
你这里的这三十个人，加上受伤的三个，你无法召唤他们，
Of these 30 that you have here, plus the three that are injured and you could not summon them,
De estos 30 que tenés aquí, más los tres que están lesionados y no pudiste convocarlos,
26 名球员的名单是来自那里，还是有更多球员不在场并且其中三人受伤了？
Will the list of 26 come from there or do you have more players who are not here and in those three injured?
¿De allí saldrá la lista de 26 o vos tenés más jugadores que no están aquí y en esos tres lesionados?
马丁内斯、利桑德罗和劳塔罗。
Martínez, Lisandro and Lautaro.
Martínez, Lisandro y Lautaro.
或者从那里出炉北美世界杯26强名单。
or from there the list of 26 for the World Cup in North America will come out.
o de allí saldrá la lista de 26 para el Mundial de Norteamérica.
原则上他们是...
In principle they are...
En principio son...
他们就是这些，但我们愿意看到像这样的球员......
They are these, but we are open to seeing players like the case of...
Son estos, pero estamos abiertos a ver jugadores como el caso de...
现在来的男孩们，表现都很好。
of the boys who have come now, boys who are doing well.
de los chicos que han venido ahora, chicos que lo están haciendo bien.
他们可能有机会，为什么不认为在过去的几个月里这可能会发生。
that they may have a chance and why not think that in the last few months it may happen.
que pueden tener oportunidad y por qué no pensar que en los últimos meses puede pasar.
还有其他男孩也没有来，你没有提到他们的名字，我们也在跟踪他们。
There are other boys who have not come too and who you did not name, who we are also following.
Hay otros chicos que no han venido también y que no los nombraste, que también los estamos siguiendo.
一切都取决于孩子们如何到达、他们的状况如何。
and everything will depend on how the kids arrive, how they are.
y todo dependerá de cómo lleguen los chicos, de cómo estén.
不仅在伤害层面，而且在伤害层面
not only at the level of injuries but at the level of
no sólo a nivel de lesiones sino a nivel de
比赛的最后，重要的是他们在各个方面都表现出色。
of the game, in the end it is important that they do well in all aspects.
de juego, al final es importante que lleguen bien en todos los aspectos.
或者最接近其潜力，这就是......
or the closest to its potential and that's what...
o lo más cercano a su potencial y eso es lo que...
我们将对此提出上诉并决定最终名单。
to which we will appeal and decide the final list.
a lo que apelaremos y decidiremos la lista final.
我们已经告诉他们，我们在周一当天的第一次谈话中就明确表示了这一点。
We already told them, we made it clear in the first talk of the day on Monday.
A ellos ya se lo dijimos, se lo dejamos en claro en la primer charla del día del lunes.
他们知道这里的利害关系。
and they are aware of what is at stake here.
y son conscientes de lo que se juegan acá.
不幸的是，那些让我们获胜的人，我们永远感激他们。
Unfortunately, those who have made us win, we are eternally grateful to them.
Lamentablemente los que nos han hecho ganar, estamos eternamente agradecidos a ellos.
但不幸的是我希望这将是一生。
but unfortunately I hope it will be for life.
pero lamentablemente ojalá sea para toda la vida.
最后的冠军可能是我们，但我们还要面对另一届世界杯。
The last champion may be us, but we have to face another World Cup.
el último campeón seamos nosotros, pero hay que afrontar otro Mundial.
我们需要优秀、有能力的人，这就是我们在决定名单时要做的事情。
And we need people who are well, capable, and that's what we will do when we decide on the list.
Y necesitamos gente que esté bien, capaz, y eso es lo que haremos cuando decidimos la lista.
莱昂内尔，你好吗？
Leonel, how are you?
Leónel, ¿cómo estás?
在这里，在中心。
Here, in the center.
Acá, en el centro.
莱安德罗·阿尔维斯（Leandro Alves），ESPM。
Leandro Alves, for ESPM.
Leandro Alves, para ESPM.
最近几周，有很多关于可能召唤安赫尔·迪玛丽亚的声音。
There was a lot of noise in recent weeks with a possible call for Ángel Di María.
Hubo mucho ruido en las últimas semanas con una posible convocatoria de Ángel Di María.
你跟他说话，你没有说话，你会喜欢它，你梦想它。
You talked to him, you didn't talk, you would like it, you dream about it.
Hablaste con él, no hablaste, te gustaría, lo soñás.
对此你有什么不能说的？
What can't you say about that?
¿Qué no podés decir de eso?
我不知道噪音。
I don't know the noise.
No sé el ruido.
我和他的关系最好，事实上他写信给我，我在圣诞节和新年回复了他，他感谢了我。
I have the best relationship with him, in fact he wrote to me and I responded for Christmas and New Year, he thanked me.
tengo la mejor relación con él, de hecho me escribió y le respondí para Navidad y año nuevo, me agradeció.
不，相反，我祝贺自己新年，也祝贺他。
No, rather, I congratulate myself on the new year and I congratulate him.
No, mejor dicho, me felicito el año nuevo y yo a él.
但我认为这对每个人来说都是一个话题。
But I think it's a bit more of a topic for everyone.
pero yo creo que es un tema un poco más de todos.
气氛，他说得很清楚。
the atmosphere, which he made clear.
el ambiente, que él lo dejó claro.
从这个角度来看，那天我们也很清楚……
and from that point of view we also had it quite clear the day that...
y desde ese punto de vista nosotros también lo tuvimos bastante claro el día que...
我们已经与他交谈过，但他今天不在。
We have spoken with him and he is not here today.
hemos hablado con él y hoy no está.
我很高兴收到你的礼物，因为除了...
I am happy for your present because apart from...
Yo estoy feliz por su presente porque aparte...
他看起来很高兴，这是最重要的。
He seems happy and that is the most important thing.
Se lo nota feliz y eso es lo más importante.
他给了我们很多。
He has given us a lot.
Nos ha dado un montón.
我相信这个阶段已经结束，或者至少我们是这么理解的。
It is a stage that I believe is finished or at least that is how we understood it.
Es una etapa que creo que es terminada o por lo menos nosotros así lo entendimos.
好吧，我们已经转向了另一个方向，有一些年轻男孩正在落后，他们想要成为
and well we have turned the other way, there are young boys who are pushing behind and who want to be
y bueno hemos virado para otro lado, hay chicos jóvenes que van empujando atrás y que quieren estar
但是，嘿，大家都知道，我和他的关系是最好的。
But hey, everyone knows, the best relationship I have with him.
Pero bueno, todos saben, la mejor relación que tengo con él.
我希望他能像现在这样继续打球。
I hope he continues playing like he has been doing until now.
Ojalá siga jugando como hasta ahora.
莱昂内尔，你好吗？
Leonel, how are you?
Leonel, ¿cómo estás?
Narela 为 Dissports 进行直播。
Narela goes live for Disports.
Narela se entra en vivo para Disports.
您如何看待现在的佛朗哥·马斯坦托诺？
How do you see the present Franco Mastantuono?
¿Cómo ves el presente Franco Mastantuono?
以及为什么他的电话可能是第二次。
-  -
太感谢了。
and why his call was perhaps in a second instance.
y a qué se debió que la convocatoria de él haya sido quizás en una segunda instancia.
La convocatoria 非常简单，但很有趣。
Thank you so much.
Muchas gracias.
由于我们只打一场比赛，所以我们无法让球员填满，这毫无用处，而且不仅仅是他和其他许多人。
The call is very simple and we are going to play a single game.
La convocatoria es muy simple y vamos a jugar un solo partido.
让他来到这里，当他们告诉我们还有第二场比赛时，我们就宣布了比赛。
and since we were going to play only one game we couldn't fill ourselves with players, it was useless and not just him and many others.
y como íbamos a jugar un solo partido no nos podíamos llenar de jugadores era inútil y no solo él y otros tantos
我很重视想要去那里的愿望。
to have him here and when they told us that there was a second game we called it.
de tenerlo acá y cuando nos avisaron que había un segundo partido lo convocamos.
因为有时，我并不是说这是错误的，但有时他们会下飞机
and I value the desire to want to be there.
y valoro las ganas de querer estar.
他们问男孩们，你认为他后来给你打电话是什么？
because sometimes, and I'm not saying it's wrong, but sometimes they get off the plane
porque a veces, y no digo que esté mal, pero a veces se bajan del avión
谢天谢地，他们是...
and they ask the boys, what do you think that he called you later?
y le preguntan a los chicos, ¿qué te parece que te haya convocado después?
他们真的很棒，因为现实是它是后来被称为的，因为只有一场比赛
They are really great because the reality is that it was called later because there was only one game
son grandes de verdad porque la realidad es que se convocó después porque había solo un partido
我们对他很满意，他是一个我一直说的男孩，他今年 18 岁了。
And we are happy with him, he is a boy that I always said, he is 18 years old.
Y estamos contentos con él, es un chico que yo siempre lo dije, tiene 18 años.
谢谢大家！
Thank you all!
¡Gracias a todos!
我从八年前开始，并没有比现在在博卡踢球的男孩走得更远。
I started eight years ago and without going any further than the boy who is playing in Boca now.
Inicié ocho años y sin ir más lejos del chico que está jugando en Boca ahora.
阿兰达、托马斯来和我们一起训练。
Aranda, Tomás, has come to train with us.
Aranda, Tomás, ha venido a entrenar con nosotros.
他和佛朗哥同岁。
He is the same age as Franco.
Tiene la misma edad de Franco.
我的意思是弗朗哥是个男孩。
By this I mean that Franco is a boy.
Con esto quiero decir que Franco es chico.
你必须给它时间，对吧？
and you have to give it time, right?
y hay que darle tiempo, ¿no?
他身处一个要求非常非常高的俱乐部。
and he is in a very demanding, very demanding club.
y está en un club muy exigente, muy exigente.
我认为他是世界上要求最高的人，这也许会让一切都被放大。
I think he is the most demanding in the world and that perhaps makes everything magnified.
Yo creo que es el más exigente del mundo y eso hace que a lo mejor todo se magnifique.
对我来说，他理解这一点就足够了，他理解他的处境，并且它会从我们身上体现出来。
It is enough for me that he understands it, that he understands his situation and it will come out of us.
a mí me basta con que él lo entienda, que entienda su situación y de nosotros saldrá
所有的遏制，最重要的是他知道……
all the containment and above all that he knows that...
toda la contención y sobre todo que sepa que...
一点一点地，他的职业生涯才刚刚开始，他必须向上，这是最重要的事情
that here little by little and that his career is just beginning and that he has to go upwards that is the most important thing
que aquí poco a poco y que su carrera recién empieza y que tiene que ir ascendente eso es lo más importante
下午好。
Good afternoon.
Buenas tardes.
红色电台的古斯塔沃·亚罗克。
Gustavo Yarroch for Radio La Red.
Gustavo Yarroch para Radio La Red.
我想问你，关于世界杯之前六月举行的友谊赛，你有什么信息。
I want to ask you what information you have about the friendlies scheduled for June, before the World Cup.
Te quiero preguntar qué información tenés sobre los amistosos previstos para junio, para antes del mundial.
然后向您咨询备战世界杯的事宜。
and then consult you about preparation for the World Cup.
y después consultarte por la preparación para el mundial.
你是不是像……？
Are you being like...?
¿Está siendo como...?
你想要的，正如你所描绘的。
you wanted, as you diagrammed.
vos querías, como vos diagramaste.
原则上，这个日期并不像世界杯后所知道的那样。
In principle, this date was not as it was known after the World Cup.
En principio esta fecha no, no fue como se sabía después del Mundial.
因为我们是在世界杯之后才知道决赛的。
because we found out about the final after the World Cup.
porque nosotros nos enteramos de la finalísima después del Mundial.
当我去看世界杯抽签时，决赛还没有正式结束。
When I go to the World Cup draw, the final was still not official.
Cuando yo voy al sorteo del Mundial todavía la finalísima no estaba oficializada.
从那里我们计划玩
and from there we plan to play
y a partir de ahí nosotros planificamos jugar
与西班牙和卡塔尔。
with Spain and with Qatar.
con España y con Catar.
六月比赛结束后，我知道塞尔维亚将是其中之一。
and after the June games I understand that one will be Serbia.
y después de los partidos de junio tengo entendido que uno va a ser Serbia.
我明白这一点。
I understand that.
Tengo entendido eso.
我们向塞尔维亚教练组提出了要求。
We have asked for it thanks to the Serbian coaching staff.
Lo hemos pedido gracias al cuerpo técnico de Serbia.
阿尔塞诺，我们已经能够与他交谈以及他是否可以参加比赛。
to Arseno and we have been able to talk to him and if he can play.
a Arseno y hemos podido hablar con él y si se puede jugar.
我认为一个对手将是塞尔维亚，另一个对手是我们……
I think one rival will be Serbia and the other we are...
creo que un rival será Serbia y el otro estamos...
悬而未决，但是原则上规划超出了这个范围......
pending, but yes in principle the planning goes beyond this...
pendiente, pero sí en principio la planificación va más allá de este...
这个日期肯定已经改变了，因为它就是这样，但与我们所做的一切完全无关。
-  -
就是这样。
of this date, which has surely changed because it is like that, but totally unrelated to everything we do.
de esta fecha, que seguramente ha cambiado porque es así, pero ajeno totalmente a todo lo nuestro.
最重要的是，古斯塔沃，他们很好地到达了终点。
It is what it is.
Es lo que hay.
当然，是的，我们都想踢球，也许和优秀的球队一起踢球。
The most important thing, Gustavo, is that they reach the end well.
Lo más importante, Gustavo, es que lleguen bien al final.
球队希望与最好的球队比赛，但是......
Of course yes, we all want to play and maybe with the good teams.
Claro que sí, que todos queremos jugar y a lo mejor con las buenas selecciones.
但这也很重要。
and the teams want to play with the best teams, but...
y los equipos quieren jugar con los mejores equipos, pero...
我记得不久前，梅诺蒂告诉我们......
But it is also important.
Pero también es importante.
能在现场呆上 20 天，接受培训，这真是太好了，但那是不存在的。
I remember a while ago, Menotti told us...
Yo me acuerdo hace un tiempo, Menotti nos dijo...
今天我们有10天时间。
It's good to be able to have 20 days on the premises, train and that didn't exist.
Es que bueno poder tener 20 días en el predio, entrenar y eso no existía.
看起来这并不有趣，但对我们来说却非常有趣。
Today we have 10 days.
Hoy tenemos 10 días.
与毛里塔尼亚队的比赛，周六与 U-20 男孩队进行一场比赛，然后周二再次比赛，超级有趣。
with Mauritania, playing a game on Saturday with the U-20 boys and then playing again on Tuesday, super interesting.
con Mauritania, jugar el sábado con los chicos de la sub-20 un partido y después volver a jugar el martes, súper interesante.
与最好的球员一起打球的另一件事并不能向你保证任何东西，它也不能向你保证任何东西，这就是
The other thing about playing with the best does not guarantee you anything and it does not guarantee you anything, this is
no te garantiza nada lo otro de jugar con los mejores y no te garantiza nada esto es
非常明显。
more than evident.
más que evidente.
你要做的就是面对对你有利的事情并利用积极的一面。
What you have to do is face what is good for you and use the positive.
Lo que hay que hacer es afrontar lo que venga bien esto y usar lo positivo.
从那时起，结果就会告诉你你是对还是错，这不是......
From there on, the result will say whether you were right or not, which is not...
A partir de ahí después el resultado dirá si acertaste o no, que tampoco es...
这是纯数学，但这是我们所拥有的，我们将尽力做到最好。
It's pure mathematics, but it's what we have and we will try to do the best we can.
Es matemática pura, pero bueno es lo que tenemos e intentaremos hacerlo lo mejor posible.
莱昂内尔，我是 TNT 体育频道的马克西·格里罗。
Leonel, this is Maxi Grillo for TNT Sports.
Leonel, aquí Maxi Grillo para TNT Sports.
我问你当前的事件和未来。
I ask you about current events and future.
Te pregunto por actualidad y futuro.
与球队相关的新闻，如果或多或少，教练就在那里，但如果或多或少你已经定义了它。
news linked to the team, if more or less, the coach is there, but if more or less you have defined it.
actualidad vinculada al equipo, si ya más o menos, justo está el entrenador, pero si más o menos tenés definido.
明天的球队，尤其是如果梅西会在那里的话。
the team for tomorrow and especially if Messi is going to be there.
el equipo para mañana y sobre todo si va a estar Messi.
关于未来，你的未来。
And about the future, your future.
Y sobre futuro, tu futuro.
如果已经有关于续约的谈判，如果你担心的话，不，你希望之前就确定下来。
If there are already talks for the renewal, if you are worried, no, you want to have it defined before.
Si ya hay charlas para la renovación, si te preocupa, no, querés tenerlo definido antes.
或者世界杯之后。
or after the World Cup.
o después del Mundial.
嗯，原则上我们要组建的团队
Well, the team in principle we are going to put
Bueno, el equipo en principio vamos a poner
我们想看到的人和其他人的混合体......
a mix of guys that we want to see and others that...
un mix de chicos que queremos ver y otros que...
我们也希望看到这一点，特别是因为......
which we also want to see, especially because...
que también queremos ver, sobre todo porque...
因为我们想要恢复一些与说谁无关的回报，
Because we want to recover some returns that are not relevant to saying who,
Porque queremos recuperar algunos rendimientos que tampoco viene al caso de decir quién,
我需要把它拿回来，事实上我告诉了他们。
I need to get it back, in fact I told them.
Necesito recuperarlo, de hecho se los dije a ellos.
我读到我是否要参加比赛，我不知道从一开始你是否
and I read if I was going to play, I don't know if from the start if you
y leo si iba a jugar no sé si de entrada si te
另一个，但他们两个都会参加比赛。我不知道有多少分钟，但他们都会在那里，特别是因为我认为
and the other, but both of them are going to play. I don't know how many minutes, but both of them are going to be there, especially because I think that
y el otro pero va a jugar los dos no sé cuántos minutos pero va a estar los dos pues sobre todo porque creo que
让梅西再踢两场比赛对阿根廷人来说有好处吗？
Is it good for the Argentine to have Messi for two more games?
¿Es de japa para el argentino tener a Messi dos partidos más?
我们将达成政党协议。
that we are going to have the party agreements.
que lo vamos a tener los acuerdos del partido.
我们以为他不再打比赛了，我们还有两场比赛。
We thought he wasn't playing anymore and we have two more games.
que pensamos que no jugaba más y tenemos dos partidos más.
我认为这是一个很好的机会在球场上看到他，很高兴每个人都能看到他。
I think it is a nice opportunity to see him on the court, nice for everyone to see.
Yo creo que es una linda oportunidad para verlo en la cancha, linda para que todos vean.
并在您每次来到这里时享受我们所享受的一切。
and enjoy what we enjoy every time you are here.
y disfruten lo que nosotros disfrutamos cada vez que está acá.
就是这样。
It's like that.
Es así.
你必须这样对待。
You have to take it that way.
Eso hay que tomarlo de esa manera.
续约，嗯，马蒂正在和总统谈话。
The renewal, well, Mati is talking to the President.
La renovación, bueno, Mati está hablando con el Presidente.
事实上，我并不是说我不担心，但今天我的重点是世界杯。
The truth is, I'm not saying that I don't worry, but today my focus is on the World Cup.
La verdad, no digo que no me preocupe, pero hoy mi foco está en el mundial.
接下来的事就不再由我决定了，但是……
The rest after that is no longer up to me, but...
El resto después ya no depende de mí, pero...
我们将看看未来会发生什么，但目前这是全球土壤。
We'll see what happens in the future, but for now it's global soil.
ya veremos que pasa en un futuro, pero por ahora es suelo mundial.
你好，利奥，这里。
Hello Leo, here.
Hola Leo, acá.
福克斯体育频道的马里亚诺·阿尔马达。
Mariano Almada from Fox Sports.
Mariano Almada de Fox Sports.
人们非常兴奋，你知道这一点，你就生活在其中。
People are very excited, you know it, you live it.
La gente está muy ilusionada, lo sabés, lo vivís.
当你来到阿根廷时，球场的门票立刻就被抢购一空，每次球队比赛时，门票总是被抢购一空。
When you come to Argentina, the stadium sells out immediately, it always sells out every time the team plays.
Cuando venís a Argentina agotó las entradas enseguida en la cancha de boca, agota siempre cada vez que juega la selección.
大家热情高涨，宣传力度很大，我想你们更欣赏它。
There is a lot of enthusiasm, the publicity that exists is great and I think you appreciated it even more.
Hay mucha ilusión, la publicidad que existe está buenísima y creo que lo sebaste más aún.
人们，用你所说的话来捍卫他们。
people, with what you said, to defend them.
a la gente, con lo que dijiste, de defenderla.
事实上，看到你这么说对每个人来说都是难以置信的。
The truth is that seeing you saying that was incredible for everyone.
La verdad que verte diciendo eso fue increíble para todos.
是的，事实。
Yes, the truth.
Sí, la verdad.
但是，嘿，说真的，我希望你向那些真正......
But hey, seriously, I would like you to give a message to people who really...
Pero bueno, hablando en serio, un mensaje me gustaría que le des a la gente que realmente...
她对这两场比赛感到非常兴奋；她卖完了第一个，并将卖掉第二个。
She is very excited about these two matches; she sold out the first and is going to sell out the second.
Está muy ilusionada con estos dos partidos que agotó el primero y va a agotar el segundo.
以及即将发生的事情。
and with what is coming.
y con lo que se viene.
好吧，对于游戏来说，我认为它很漂亮，我喜欢它，而对于其余的，它是......
Well, for the games I think it's muddy that it's pretty, that I enjoy it, for the rest it's...
Bueno, para los partidos me parece barro que esté lillonada, que disfrute, para lo otro es...
另一项非常困难，孩子，那是……
The other one is very difficult, boy, it's something...
El otro es muy difícil, muchacho, es algo...
有希望，不仅仅是有希望，而且谈论世界杯是一件……
Promising, not just promising, but talking about a World Cup is something...
Prometer, no solo prometer, sino hablar de un Mundial es algo...
令人难以置信的是，你可以...
It's incredible to think that you can...
Es algo increíble pensar en que se pueda...
再说一遍，在我看来，这是某事，承诺某事......
to repeat again, it seems to me that it is something, to promise something...
volver a repetir, me parece que es algo, prometer algo...
这是不可想象的，特别是因为它所面临的困难，我们将会看到。
has been unthinkable, especially because of the difficulty it has and we will see.
ha impensado, sobre todo por la dificultad que tiene y ya veremos.
保证最大程度的妥协
We guarantee what you see from the team maximum commitment maximum
garantizamos lo que se ve del equipo máximo compromiso máximo
竞争，我们不会让事情变得容易，即使是......
competition, we will not make things easy even for the...
competencia, no le pondremos las cosas fáciles incluso a los...
对于同一个队友来说，更不用说对手了。
to the same teammates among themselves and not to mention the rivals.
a los mismos compañeros entre ellos y ni hablar a los rivales.
但世界杯是一件好事，事实上我认为
but the world cup is a good thing, in fact I think
pero el mundial es algo bueno, de hecho creo que
并不是因为我是教练，我认为阿根廷当之无愧地赢得了上届世界杯，但有很多世界杯......
And not because I was the coach, I think Argentina deservedly won the last World Cup, but there are many World Cups that...
y no porque yo haya sido el entrenador, creo que Argentina sí que ganó merecidamente el último mundial, pero hay muchísimos mundiales que...
当之无愧的人却没有获胜，这就带来了困难。
that the one who deserves does not win, then that gives the difficulty it has.
que no gana el que merece, entonces eso da la dificultad que tiene.
对我来说，人们感到认同就足够了，从逻辑上讲，我们都想要……
It is enough for me that people feel identified, logically we all want...
A mí me basta con que la gente se sienta identificada, lógicamente todos queremos...
达到最大值但继续
reach the maximum but continue with that
llegar al máximo pero seguir con esa
我们所拥有的信念以及......
That conviction that we have and that...
Esa convicción que tenemos y esa...
我们在每场比赛中展示的以及人们认同我们的一切都是最好的。
Everything that we demonstrate every game and that people identify with us is the best.
Todo lo que demostramos cada partido y que la gente siente identificada para nosotros es lo máximo.
首先，享受这些比赛，享受观看球队比赛，然后我们看看接下来会发生什么。
First, enjoy these games, enjoy watching the team, and then we'll see what happens next.
primero que disfruten de estos partidos, que disfruten de ver al equipo y después lo siguiente ya veremos.
莱昂内尔在这里，卢西亚娜是里瓦达维亚广播电台的。
Leonel here, Luciana for Radio Rivadavia.
Leonel acá, Luciana para Radio Rivadavia.
我问你，你现在看墙怎么样？
I ask you, how are you seeing walls right now?
Te pregunto, ¿cómo estás viendo paredes en esta actualidad?
在博卡以及你认为他在科洛巴科的位置是什么，无论是作为你球队的左后卫还是中场球员。
-  -
谢谢。
in Boca and also in what position do you think of him at the colobarco, whether as a left back or as a midfielder for your team.
en Boca y también en qué puesto lo pensás al colobarco, si de lateral izquierdo o de volante tu equipo.
好吧，莱安德罗，我们已经和他谈过了，我在赛季开始前谈过。
Thank you.
Gracias.
对一些事情发表评论。
Well, Leandro, we have spoken with him, I spoke before the start of the season.
Bueno, Leandro, hemos hablado con él, hablé antes del inicio de la temporada.
他是一位我们已经知道他控球能力如何的球员。
commenting on some things.
comentando algunas cosas.
优先考虑他的球队和阿根廷足球。
He is a player who we already know what he is like with the ball.
Es un jugador que ya sabemos lo que es con la pelota.
我们谈论过的事情，无论好坏，我总是保密。
that prioritizes his team and Argentine football.
que jerarquiza a su equipo y al fútbol argentino.
我很了解他，他也很清楚我们想从他那里得到什么。
The things we have talked about, good and bad, I always keep to myself.
Las cosas que hemos hablado, buenas y malas, siempre me las guardo.
能够和他们谈论这个事情真是太好了。
I know him well and he knows very well what we want from him.
Lo conozco de sobra y sabe muy bien lo que pretendemos de él.
瓦伦丁，好吧，左后卫已经参与了一份可能的名单
It's good to be able to talk about that with them.
Está bueno poder hablar eso con ellos.
它给你一个选择，如果在某个时候你必须玩三个你可以做到，但是......
and Valentín, well, the left back has played in having a possible list
y Valentín, bueno, ha jugado el lateral izquierdo en tener una posible lista
按理来说，今天不是他的位置，他做得很好。
It gives you the option that if at some point you have to play three you can do it, but...
te da la variante de que si en algún momento tiene que jugar de tres lo puede hacer, pero...
作为一名中场球员，他可以踢所有三个中场位置。
Logically, today is not his position, he is doing very well.
lógicamente hoy no es su posición, lo está haciendo muy bien.
这是一个很好的
As a midfielder, he can play in all three midfield positions.
de centro campista, puede jugar en las tres posiciones del centro de campo.
我们可以打赌，或者最重要的是，因为我认为他已经采取了要求他迈出的那一步。
and it is a very good one
y es una muy buena
他肩负起球队的重担，球队几乎都在踢球
the bet that we can have or above all because I think he has taken that step that was asked of him.
la apuesta que podemos tener o sobre todo porque creo que ha dado ese paso que se le pedía.
达到他想要的，我们很高兴。
He has shouldered the team and practically the team plays
Se ha echado el equipo al hombro y prácticamente el equipo juega
我们会给他机会参加这些比赛并展示他的价值。
to what he wants and we are happy.
a lo que él quiere y estamos contentos.
将军，这里是《El Diario Lé》的尼科·杰拉多 (Nico Gerardo)。
We will give him the opportunity to play in these games and show what he is worth.
le daremos la oportunidad de jugar en estos partidos y que pueda demostrar lo que vale.
莱昂内尔对于参加世界杯总是非常小心，他总是谈论日常，等待，但是......
Lionel was always quite careful about playing in the World Cup, he always talked about day to day, waiting, but...
Lionel siempre fue bastante cuidadoso con el tema de jugar el Mundial, siempre habló del día a día, de esperar, pero...
对阵阿尔及利亚的首场比赛，我们的积分为 82 分。
We are at 82 for the debut against Algeria.
Estamos a 82 para el debut contra Argelia.
问题是里奥现在怎么样，如果你和他交谈过，我们是否会在世界杯上见到他。
The question is how is Leo and if we are going to see him in the World Cup if you spoke to him.
La pregunta es cómo está Leo y si lo vamos a ver en el mundial si hablaste con él.
嗯，这个问题对他来说更重要，但就我而言，你已经知道我的想法了。
Well, that's a question that's more for him, but on my part you already know what I think.
Bueno, esa es una pregunta que es más para él, pero de mi parte ya saben lo que pienso.
我将尽一切可能做到这一点 我们将尽一切可能做到这一点
and I will do everything possible so that it is and we will do everything possible so that
y haré todo lo posible para que esté y haremos todo lo posible para que
事实上，我相信为了足球的利益，它应该存在，但我不是决定者。
The truth is that I believe that for the good of football it should be there, but I am not the one who decides.
La verdad que yo creo que para el bien del fútbol tendría que estar, pero yo no soy el que decide.
我总是说，这将是他，这将是他的心情、他的头脑、他的身体状态。
and I always said it, it will be him and it will be his mood, his head, his physical state.
y siempre lo dije, será él y será su estado de ánimo, su cabeza, su estado físico.
这很困难，因为不仅阿根廷人想看，每个人都想看。
It's difficult, because not only Argentines want to see it, everyone wants to see it.
Es difícil, porque no solo los argentinos lo quieren ver, lo quieren ver todos.
那么我们作为教练就会陷入两难的境地。
Then we will be in a dilemma, we as coaches.
Después estaremos en la disyuntiva, nosotros como entrenadores.
当他在的时候，如果他在那里打整场比赛，如果他不在那里打球，但我希望他在那里。
when he is, if he is there to play the whole game, if he is not there to play, but I want him to be there.
cuando esté, si está para jugar todo el partido, si no está para jugar, pero yo quiero que esté.
但他是做出决定的人。
But he is the one who decides.
Pero es él el que decide.
我不会站在这里说，不，我要看看我是否放了它。
I'm not going to stand here and say, no, I'm going to see if I put it or not.
Yo no me voy a poner acá a decir, no, voy a ver si lo pongo o no lo pongo.
是他，是他，还有……
It's him, it's him and...
Es él, es él y...
并赢得了决定权。
and earned the right to decide.
y se ganó el derecho a poder decidir.
安心。
With peace of mind.
Con tranquilidad.
我们对此并不着急。
We are not in any hurry about that.
Nosotros no tenemos ningún apuro por eso.
我们知道，无论他做出什么决定，对球队和他来说都是最好的。
and we know that whatever he decides will be best for both the team and him.
y sabemos que lo que decida será lo mejor tanto para el equipo como para él.
我们希望如此，但我不能告诉你更多。
We hope so, but I can't tell you much more.
Esperemos que sea que sí, pero no te puedo decir mucho más.
莱昂内尔，你好吗？
Leonel, how are you doing?
Leonel, ¿cómo te va?
尼古拉斯·梅 (Nicolás May) 效力于 Cadena 3 Santa Fe 和 Central Deportiva。
Nicolás May for Cadena 3 Santa Fe and Central Deportiva.
Nicolás May para Cadena 3 Santa Fe y la Central Deportiva.
两个问题，你好吗？
Two questions, how are you?
Dos preguntas, ¿cómo estás vos?
展望2023年3月21日的本届世界杯，我们都欣喜若狂。
Looking ahead to this World Cup, on March 21, 2023, we are all euphoric.
de cara a este mundial, el 21 de marzo del 2023, estamos todos eufóricos.
你问他们是否感觉自己像冠军，我们都说是。
You asked if they feel like champions, we all said yes.
Preguntaste si se sienten campeones, decimos todos que sí.
很多时间过去了。
A lot of time passed.
Pasó muchísimo tiempo.
你必须重塑自己，提供工具。
and you have to reinvent yourself, give tools.
y hay que reinventarse, dar herramientas.
你对此怎么样？
How are you for that?
¿Cómo estás vos para eso?
因为有一支雄心勃勃的队伍。
Because there is an ambitious squad.
Porque hay un plantel ambicioso.
贪婪、竞争，一方面是这个，另一方面是……
voracious, competitive, on the one hand it is this and that...
voraz, competitivo, por un lado es esto y lo otro...
我知道你很少出现在社交媒体上，但他们会对你发表评论......
I know you're not on social media much, but they comment on you...
Sé que no estás mucho en redes sociales, pero te comentan...
很多人认为阿根廷队在即将到来的世锦赛上将会令人失望。
There are many people who believe that Argentina is going to disappoint in this upcoming world championship.
que hay mucha gente que cree que Argentina va a desilusionar en este campeonato mundial que se viene.
不，但是有人说它会进展顺利，也有人说它会变坏。
No, but as there is the one who says it will go well, there is the one who says it will go bad.
No, pero como está el que dice que va a ir bien, está el que dice que va a ir mal.
我不知道该告诉你什么，因为我不能，首先我认为这是......
I don't know what to tell you about that because I can't, first of all I think it's something...
No sé qué decirte a eso porque no me pongo, primero que creo que es algo...
一个人问一个女人发生了什么事，一个人说好，另一个人说不好，这是很正常的，这是统计数据。
It is normal for one to ask a woman what is going on and one says good, the other will say bad, they are statistics.
Es normal que uno le pregunte a un mujer qué va y uno dice bien, el otro dirá mal, son estadísticas.
世界杯非常复杂。
The World Cup is very complicated.
El Mundial es muy complicado.
非常复杂，所以现在就开始做或者保证，我不这么认为。
terribly complicated, so start doing it now or promise, I don't think so.
terriblemente complicado, entonces ponerse a hacer ahora o prometer, me parece que no.
我们很好，我们在一起...
We are fine, we are with...
Estamos bien, estamos con...
你赢了，我们知道我们的对手会和我们比赛
you win, we are aware that our rivals are going to play us
ganas, somos conscientes de que los rivales nos van a jugar
也许不同，因为确实是最后一个冠军......
maybe different because it is true that being the last champion...
a lo mejor diferente porque sí que es verdad que al ser el último campeón...
它有额外的功能，但是嘿，重要的是要知道我们不玩什么以及球队将由谁组成。
It has that extra, but hey, the important thing is to know what we are not playing and who the team is going to be.
tiene ese extra, pero bueno, lo importante es saber lo que no jugamos y que el equipo va a estar.
然后从那时起，关于足球，我们已经知道会发生什么，但我不是一个经常观看网络的人，但是
then from there on football we already know what can happen but I'm not one to watch the networks much but
después a partir de ahí el fútbol ya sabemos lo que puede pasar pero no soy de mirar mucho las redes pero
我认为这不是网络问题，而是......
I think it's not so much a network issue, but rather...
Creo que no es un tema tanto de redes, sino que...
最后他问你一个问题，你觉得你怎样才能做得好？
At the end he asks you a question, how do you think you will do well?
Al final te hace una pregunta, ¿cómo crees que te va a ir bien?
比例是70到30...
The percentage was 70 to 30...
El porcentaje era de 70 a 30...
又来了 30 多个，或者反过来，我不知道，它们是统计数据。
Here comes another 30 more or the other way around, I don't know, they are statistics.
ahí viene otro 30 que más o al revés, no sé, son estadísticas.
和人们的想法，人们最终给出他们的意见，幸运的是他们玩。
and people's thoughts, people ultimately give their opinion and luckily they play.
y pensamiento de la gente, la gente al final opina y por suerte juegan.
球员们，我们希望他们一切都好。
the players and we hope they are well.
los jugadores y esperemos que estén bien.
现在，当世界杯开始时，事情就开始了……
Now, when the World Cup starts it starts a little...
Ahora bien, cuando empiece el Mundial empieza un poquito...
你想让我冷静，但我假装，我假装，但不，不。
You want me to be calm, but I pretend, I pretend, but no, no.
Ustedes quieren que yo estoy tranquilo, pero aparento, aparento, pero no, no.
教练们...
The coaches...
Los entrenadores...
我们从来不平静，是的，确实如此......
We are never calm, yes it is true that...
nunca estamos tranquilos, sí que es verdad que...
我很安心，因为我有一个团队在背后支持我，我知道他们会付出一切，这很好。
I have peace of mind that I have a group behind that I know is going to give everything and that is good.
que la tranquilidad la tengo de que tengo un grupo atrás que sé que va a dar todo y eso está bueno.
但即将到来的是勇敢的
but what is coming is is is is brave and that
pero lo que se viene es es es bravo y eso
这是世界杯，我们知道这有多困难。
It's a World Cup and we know how difficult it is.
Es un Mundial y sabemos la dificultad que tiene.
莱昂内尔，这里是田纳西州的巴勃罗·布鲁内托。
Leonel, here Pablo Brunetto for TN.
Leonel, acá Pablo Brunetto para TN.
你谈到了最后的，在一般层面上，我想问你......
You talked about the very final, at a general level, I want to ask you...
Hablaste de la finalísima, a nivel general, te quiero preguntar...
特别是因为阿根廷不同意27号比赛。
particularly because Argentina did not agree to play on the 27th.
particularmente porque Argentina no aceptó jugar el 27.
在意大利，如果所有这些骚动都是关于友谊赛和
in Italy and if all this commotion there is regarding the friendlies and the
en Italia y si todo este revuelo que hay en cuanto a los amistosos y las
阿根廷最近的友谊赛的等级制度，是我们媒体的问题还是也让你感到有点噪音？
The hierarchy of friendlies that Argentina has had in recent times, is it something of our press or does it also make a bit of noise to you?
la jerarquía de los amistosos que ha tenido la Argentina en el último tiempo, ¿es algo nuestro de la prensa o a ustedes también les hace un poco de ruido?
阿根廷近段时间的友谊赛的等级制度。
The hierarchy of the friendlies that Argentina has had in recent times.
La jerarquía de los amistosos que ha tenido Argentina en el último tiempo.
事实是，我们可能与欧洲对手比赛的唯一窗口
The truth is that the only window that we could possibly have played with a European rival
La verdad es que la única ventana que posiblemente hubiéramos podido jugar con algún rival europeo
我说可能是因为那是在十一月
and I say possibly because it was in November
y digo posiblemente porque fue en noviembre
我想我们去了安哥拉，我们要去印度。
that we went to Angola and we were going to India, I think.
que nosotros fuimos a Angola y íbamos a la India, creo.
是的，去印度。
Yes, to India.
Sí, a la India.
这是唯一的一个，因为欧洲人，那些不受国家联盟约束的人，可以在那个窗口进行比赛。
It was the only one because the Europeans, those who were free from the Nation League, could play in that window.
Era la única porque los europeos, los que quedaban libres de la Nation League, podían jugar a esa ventana.
我们总是不得不扔掉窗户的其余部分
We have always had to throw the rest of the window
El resto de la ventana siempre hemos tenido que tirar
竞争对手或非洲人或美国。
rivals or Africans or America.
rivales o africanos o de América.
就是这样，没有其他真理，十一月就是这样。
And that's it, there is no other truth, in November and that's it.
Y es eso, no hay otra verdad, en noviembre y está.
关于27号，我觉得时间到了就晚了，我们不知道要去哪里玩。
Regarding the 27th, I think that when the time arrived it was delayed, we didn't know where we were going to play.
Con respecto al día 27, creo que cuando llegó el tiempo se retrasaba, no sabíamos dónde íbamos a jugar.
或者更确切地说，只有西班牙，
or rather, the option was only Spain,
o mejor dicho, la opción era solo España,
物流不再一样了，我们不得不取消所有旅行，我本来打算周一去旅行。
The logistics were no longer the same, we had to cancel all trips, I was going to travel on Monday.
Nosotros la logística ya no era la misma, nosotros tuvimos que cancelar todos los viajes, yo iba a viajar el lunes.
多哈之行被取消，因为从逻辑上讲，这不是一场比赛，我们必须寻找新的替代方案。
The trip to Doha was canceled because, logically, it was not a game, we had to look for new alternatives.
A Doha se canceló el viaje porque, lógicamente, no se jugaba, había que buscar nuevas alternativas.
We, the props and all the people who travel, travel from here, don't travel, aren't here for an hour and a half.
Nosotros, la utilería y toda la gente que viaja, viaja de acá, no viaja, no está una hora y media.
这并不容易。
It's not easy.
no es fácil.
因此，花两三天的时间非常重要。
So taking those two or three days for that is very important.
Entonces, tomarse esos dos o tres días para eso es muy importante.
然后还有其他可以谈论的事情，但这就是现实。
Then there is everything else that can be talked about, but that is the reality.
después está todo lo otro que se pueda hablar, pero la realidad es esa.
从这里到那里的旅行，你必须计划它。
to travel from here to there and you have to plan it.
para viajar de acá para allá y hay que planearlo.
如果由于您计划去某个地方并且您的预订失败而导致计划失败。
And if plans fall apart because you were planning to go somewhere and your reservations fall apart.
y si los planes se caen porque tenías pensado ir a un lado y se te caen las reservas.
随团人员有60人、70人、80人。
There are 60, 70, 80 people who travel with the delegation.
Son 60, 70, 80 personas que viajan con la delegación.
这并不像看起来那么容易，这就是现实。
It's not as easy as it seems, that's the reality.
No es tan fácil como parece, esa es la realidad.
莱昂内尔，你怎么在这里？
Leonel, how are you here?
Leonel, ¿qué tal aquí?
Cadena 3 的克劳迪奥·西克里奥尼 (Claudio Ciclioni)。
Claudio Ciclioni from Cadena 3.
Claudio Ciclioni de Cadena 3.
我想问你，你说……
I wanted to ask you about, you said...
Te quería preguntar acerca, decías...
后面的球员必须表现出色，我们必须捍卫冠军。
The guys at the back have to be pushing well and we have to defend the title.
Tienen que estar los chicos de atrás bien empujando y hay que defender el título.
关于一些受重伤的冠军的一些具体案例。
about some specific cases of some champions who have had significant injuries.
sobre algunos casos puntuales de algunos campeones que han tenido lesiones importantes.
多久，例如利桑德罗·马丁内斯，你会……多久
How long, like Lisandro Martínez, for example, how long will you...
¿Hasta cuándo, como Lisandro Martínez, por ejemplo, hasta cuándo vos…
你会在他的层次上等待他，或者也许他已经满足了你。
You are going to wait for him at his level, or maybe he has already satisfied you.
lo vas a esperar a su nivel, o a lo mejor ya te ha conformado.
问问自己，您认为哪些球队在本届世界杯上表现出色。
and ask yourself about the teams that you consider are doing very well in terms of football at this World Cup.
y preguntarte por los equipos que consideras que llegan muy bien futbolísticamente a este Mundial.
就利桑德罗、洛塞尔索、劳塔罗而言，我们相信他们是男孩......
In the case of Lisandro, Lo Celso, Lautaro, we believe that they are boys who...
en el caso de Lisandro, de Lo Celso, de Lautaro, creemos que son chicos que...
他们受了伤，可以回归……
They have had injuries and they can return to...
han tenido lesiones y que pueden volver a...
在他们的水平上进行竞争，我们会看看这种情况何时发生，或者通过竞争来了解他们的水平。
to compete at their level and we'll see when that happens or to compete to see how they are.
a competir a su nivel y ya veremos cuando eso suceda o a competir a ver cómo están.
原则上他们会没事的，这就是我们大家的想法。
In principle they are going to be fine and that is what we all think.
en principio van a estar bien y eso es lo que todos pensamos.
然后你想要另一件吗？
And then you want the other one?
¿Y después quiere el otro?
不少于10个。
No less than 10.
No menos de 10.
至少有10支球队能够赢得世界杯。
No less than 10 teams can win the World Cup.
No menos de 10 selecciones pueden ganar el Mundial.
我不会一一列举，但不少于10个。
I'm not going to list them, but no less than 10.
No me las voy a poner a enumerar, pero no menos de 10.
有没有人能摆脱我们都知道的那些，并且你喜欢你的比赛方式？
Is there anyone that escapes the ones we all know and that you like how you are playing?
¿Alguno que escape de los que conocemos todos y que te guste cómo estás jugando?
那逃跑的又是谁呢？
And who is that escaping?
¿Y quién es ese que escapa?
我无法理解，但你不知道，有10个选择，不少于10个，我什至可能达不到他们能达到的水平……
It escapes me, not for you, there are 10 choices, no less than 10 and I may even fall short of what they can reach...
A mí me escapa, para vos no, hay 10 elecciones, no menos de 10 y capaz hasta me quedo corta que pueden llegar a...
赢得世界杯。
to win the World Cup.
a ganar el Mundial.
但我毫不怀疑有10支球队处于非常高的水平。
But I have no doubt that there are 10 teams that are at a very high level.
Pero no tengo dudas, que hay 10 selecciones que están en un nivel altísimo.
其中有非常高水平的球员，表现最好的人就会获胜。
which has very high level players and the one who does the best will win.
que tiene jugadores de altísimo nivel y ganará el que mejor lo haga.
无论谁在某个时候有那么好的运气，就像其他人一样。
whoever has that dose of luck at some point, like everyone else.
el que tenga esa dosis de suerte en algún momento, como todo el mundo.
甚至很难开始决定这十个人是谁，也许有十二个人，也可能有九个人，但是有很多，克劳迪奥，有很多。
It is difficult to even begin to decide who those ten are, maybe there are even twelve or maybe there are nine, but there are a lot, Claudio, there are a lot.
difícil ya ni ponerme a cortar quién son esas diez, capaz que hasta son doce o capaz sean nueve, pero hay un montón, Claudio, hay un montón.
下午好，路易斯·弗雷戈西，布宜诺斯艾利斯广播电台，今天的重播剧。
Good afternoon, Luis Fregosi, for Radio Buenos Aires, the play of the day.
Buenas tardes, Luis Fregosi, para Radio Buenos Aires, la jugada del día.
男孩阿兰达的照片，事实是，这是阿根廷足球中非常重要的出场。
of the boy Aranda and the truth is that it is a very important appearance in Argentine football.
del chico Aranda y la verdad que es una aparición muy importante del fútbol argentino.
在最近的训练和结束中，他的什么让你感到惊讶？
What surprised you about him in recent training sessions and finishes?
¿Qué te sorprendió de él en los entrenamientos recientes y acabeadas?
训练你已经看到它，然后问问自己是否意识到你是技术人员
trained that you had seen it and then also ask yourself if you are aware that you are the technician
entrenado que lo habías visto y después preguntarte también si sos consciente que sos el técnico
他给了梅西一座世界杯，或者实际上帮助了他，而你也将是最后一次指导他的人。
that he gave Messi a World Cup or actually helped him and that you are also going to be the one who directs him for the last time.
que le dio un mundial a Messi o lo ayudó en realidad y que también vas a ser el que lo dirija por última vez.
现在再说一遍，这次我不会哭。
Now again, I'm not going to cry this time.
Ahora otra vez, no voy a llorar esta vez.
我已经亲眼见过你了。
I had already seen you with my eyes.
Ya te había visto con re ojos.
这次你不会再哭了。
You're not going to cry this time.
No vas a llorar esta vez.
他将在最后一届世界杯上执教梅西。
He is going to coach Messi in his last World Cup.
va a entrenar a Messi en su último Mundial.
我希望，我希望。
I wish, I wish.
Ojalá, ojalá.
我想是的。
I think so.
Yo creo que sí.
我希望这是他要来的信号。
I hope it's your sign that he's coming.
Ojalá sea su señal de que viene.
好吧，我们带这个男孩来训练，而不是这个男孩。
Well, we brought this boy to train, not this boy.
Bueno, a este chico lo hemos traído a entrenar, a este chico no.
我们带阿兰达去训练，因为我们看到了你最终看到的结果。
We have brought Aranda to train because we see what you see in the end.
A Aranda lo hemos traído a entrenar porque vemos lo que ven ustedes al final.
他的外表很漂亮。
He made a nice appearance.
Hizo una linda aparición.
现在我们先不开始，看看他是否能进入世界杯，因为他也已经不年轻了。
Now let's not start, let's see if he enters the World Cup, because he's not very young either.
Ahora no empecemos, a ver si entra en el Mundial, porque tampoco es muy joven.
蒂拉，佛朗哥，我再说一遍。
Tila, by Franco, I repeat it again.
Tila, de Franco, lo vuelvo a repetir.
这表明你正在想象未来的未来。
And that indicates that you imagine the future that lies ahead.
Y eso indica que imaginate el futuro que tiene por adelante.
他有欲望，他有信心，他一对一，他是一位非常有趣的球员。
He has desire, he has confidence, he has one against one, he is a very interesting player.
Tiene gana, tiene parpajo, tiene uno contra uno, es un jugador muy interesante.
以及这些家伙玩游戏时嘴里唱的是什么
and what plays in these guys' mouths when they play in
y que juega en boca estos chicos cuando juegan en
这么大的俱乐部，博卡，河床，他们踢得像这样，这是因为他们有一些不同的东西，他训练得很好，昨天我们把它穿上了
such big clubs, Boca, River and they play like that it's because they have something different so well he has trained, yesterday we put it on
clubes tan grandes, Boca, River y juegan así es porque tienen algo diferente entonces bueno ha entrenado, ayer lo pusimos
在减少的
in a reduced
en un reducido.
青年队有这样的球员是件好事
It's good that the youth team has that type of players and that
Está bueno que la selección juvenil tenga ese tipo de jugadores y que
我们至少给他机会来和他的偶像一起训练。
That we give him the opportunity to, at least, come and train with his idols.
que nosotros le demos la oportunidad de, aunque sea, venir a entrenar con sus ídolos.
他们看到自己在血肉上与他们相似，这就是想法。
and that they see that they are like them in flesh and blood, that is the idea.
y que vean que son como ellos de carne y hueso, esa es la idea.
嗯，在项目中我希望是......
Well, in the project I hope it is...
Bueno, en el proyecto ojalá que sea...
让我成为他上届世界杯的教练，这是我们都希望的。
Let me be his coach in the last World Cup, that's what we all want.
que sea yo el entrenador de él en el último Mundial, que eso es lo que queremos todos.
莱昂内尔，你怎么在这里？
Leonel, how are you here?
Leonel, ¿qué tal acá?
是的，抱歉。
Yes, sorry.
Sí, perdón.
哦，罗巴里拉，停在这里，你可以跳。
Oh, Robarila, stop here you can jump.
Ay, Robarila, para aquí podéis saltar.
问题是您是否对此感到担忧...
The question is about whether you feel any concern regarding...
La consulta es acerca de si sentís alguna preocupación en cuanto...
与卡塔尔不同的是，旅行，恰恰是不同国家的气候。
Unlike Qatar, the trips, precisely the climate in the different states.
a diferencia de Qatar, los viajes, justamente el clima en los diferentes estados.
如果您认为这可以成为准备的一个条件。
if you think that can be a condition when it comes to preparation.
si crees que eso puede ser un condicionante a la hora de la preparación.
您还告诉我们有关位于堪萨斯州的阿根廷基地的信息。
and that you also tell us about the Argentine base that will be in Kansas.
y que también nos comentes acerca de la base de Argentina que va a ser en Kansas.
嗯，最后还是热...
Well, in the end the heat...
Bueno, al final el calor...
这对每个人来说都是一样的。
and it will be the same for everyone.
y será para todos igual.
无论如何，迈阿密美洲杯决赛已经过去了。
Yes, it is true, for example, we played the final in Miami of the Copa América.
Sí que es verdad, por ejemplo, nosotros jugamos la final en Miami de la Copa América.
是的，天气非常热，非常非常热，一直持续，但是哦，好吧。
And yes, it was very hot, very, very hot and on and on, but oh well.
y sí que hacía mucho calor, mucho, mucho y sigue, pero bueno.
竞争对手也受到了影响，但就节目本身而言，我认为这会是
The rival also suffers from it but for the show itself I think it will be
el rival también lo sufre pero para el espectáculo en sí yo creo que va a ser
不，在布埃诺，在 3 分钟的时间里，FIFA 就进入了决赛，所有的事情都已经过去了……
It's not going to be good, that's why the 3-minute stoppage that FIFA is going to see at the end, I think all of that is done so that...
No va a estar bueno, por eso el parate de 3 minutos que la FIFA va a ver al final, creo que todo eso se hace para que...
在此期间玩家可以休息
player can have a rest in the meantime
jugador pueda tener un un descanso entre tanto
上届世俱杯异常火爆。
The last Club World Cup was incredibly hot.
El último Mundial de Clubes se vio impresionante el calor.
如果有的话，最让我担心的是日程安排。
And what worries me the most, if anything, are the schedules.
y a mí lo que más me preocupa si es algo son los horarios.
既然你必须打一个我想象但我不知道的赛程表，我说也许从我的角度来看，也许你打一个大多数人都能看到的赛程表
Since you have to play a schedule that I imagine and I don't know, I say it maybe from my point of view, maybe you play a schedule where the majority can see it
como hay que jugar un horario que imagino y no lo sé, lo digo a lo mejor desde mi punto de vista, a lo mejor se juega un horario donde lo pueda ver la mayoría
世界然后关于它也许他们不适合玩家
world then about it maybe they are not the right ones for the players
mundo entonces sobre ello a lo mejor no son no son los indicados para los jugadores
但我记得这个，我想是那年的迭戈，我不知道……
but I remember this, I think it was Diego in the year, I don't know...
pero esto me acuerdo, creo que fue Diego en el año, no sé...
那场比赛是在阿兹特克球场举行的，很久以前我们就在谈论它，为此发生了一场争吵。
-  -
发生了什么？
没有什么。
-  -
就是这样。
that was played at the Azteca and how long ago we were talking about it, there was a fight about it.
que se jugó en el Azteca y de cuánto hace que estamos hablando que se peleaba por eso.
唯一可以改进的是，嘿，我们打了一整晚，整晚的所有比赛。
What happened?
¿Qué pasó?
但当然有这么多的游戏，我想这是不可能的，这就是为什么
Nothing.
Nada.
基地里的是卢法（Luifa）和胡安（Juan），还有两位老师和丹尼（Dani）。
It is what it is.
Es lo que hay.
和Beto他们一起去看了那个地方，他们说这个地方非常好，非常好，我没有去。
And the only thing that could be improved would be, hey, we played all night, all the games of the night.
Y es lo único que si se podría mejorar sería, che, jugamos la noche, todos los partidos de la noche.
他们会通过照片向我展示。
but of course there are so many games and I imagine that it is not possible that is why
pero claro hay tantos partidos y imagino que no se puede por eso que
但是，除此之外，我们不是在寻找奢华或任何东西，我们正在寻找......
And the one at the base was Luifa with Juan, the two teachers, with Dani.
Y el de la base fue Luifa con Juan, los dos profes, con Dani.
在一起，一个舒适的地方，让孩子们感到舒适，让他们感觉就像在家里一样，让他们拥有以下的最低条件
with Beto and they went to see the place, they say the place is very nice, very nice, I didn't go.
con Beto y fueron a ver el lugar, dicen que el lugar es muy bonito, muy lindo, yo no fui.
健身房靠近训练，其他就很少了。
gyms close to training and little else.
los gimnasios cerca del entrenamiento y poco más.
事实是，条件很好。
The truth is that the conditions are good.
La verdad es que las condiciones están bien.
和达法工作室内部。
and Daffa Studio Interior.
y Daffa Studio Interior.
作为一个来自内地的人，我想问你是否庆祝球员的继续出现。
As a man from the interior that you are, I want to ask you if you celebrate that players continue to appear.
Como hombre del interior que sos, te quiero preguntar si celebrás que sigan apareciendo jugadores.
出生在我们国家的内陆地区，我们知道阿根廷是一个足球国家。
Born in the interior of our country, we know that Argentina is a soccer country.
nacidos en el interior de nuestro país, sabemos que Argentina es un país futbolero.
但新的球员不断出现，事实上这个称呼中几乎有50%的球员是在内线出生的。
but new players continue to appear, in fact this call has almost 50% of players born in the interior.
pero siguen apareciendo nuevos jugadores, de hecho esta convocatoria tiene casi al 50% de jugadores nacidos en el interior.
你认为他们会给这批刚开始的新球员带来什么？
What do you think they are going to give to this new crop of players that many started out with?
¿Qué crees que le van a dar esta nueva camada de jugadores que muchos se iniciaron?
去了欧洲或世界的其他地方，但总而言之，他们是天生的和玩耍的仆人
went to Europe or another part of the world but in short they are servants born and played
se fue a Europa u otra parte del mundo pero que en definitiva son criados nacidos y jugaron
在我国的腹地深处。
in the deep interior of our country.
en el interior profundo de nuestro país.
好吧，无论如何，他们最终都是阿根廷人。
-  -
明显的。
Well, in the end they are Argentines anyway.
Bueno, al final son argentinos igual.
他确信，当我们召唤他们时，我们会看看他们来自哪里。
Obvious.
Obvio.
也许我们稍后会知道。
We look at where they are from, he is sure, when we summon them.
Nos miramos de dónde son, está seguro, cuando los convocamos.
他们询问了潘皮亚诺的情况。
Maybe we'll find out later.
A lo mejor nos damos cuenta después.
因为最终我相信文化和特质是相同的。
They asked about Pampeano.
Preguntaron de Pampeano.
好处是...
because in the end I believe that the culture and idiosyncrasy is the same.
porque al final yo creo que la cultura y la idiosincrasia es la misma.
每个省都能有一个代表，那就太壮观了。
and what's good is that...
y lo que está bueno que...
如果能搭配就很好了。
each province could have a representative, it would be spectacular.
cada provincia pueda tener un representante, sería espectacular.
还有他们带来的小男孩……
If it matches it would be good.
si coincide sería bueno.
想要在那里的巨大热情，有时太热情，太兴奋，因为他们做了一切......
And the young boys they bring...
Y los chicos jóvenes que traen...
很快，随着时间的推移，他们会学习的。
very quickly and they will learn as time goes by.
rapidísimo y van a ir aprendiendo con el paso del tiempo.
也许做出改变并更多地了解他的队友，这就是我们在这次电话会议中试图做的事情。
to maybe make a change and understand his teammates a little more, and that is what we are trying to do in this call.
a bajar a lo mejor un cambio y a entender un poco más a sus compañeros, y es lo que intentamos en esta convocatoria.
但有时欲望可以做到这一点，而且这样更好，因为他们带着这种欲望而来。
but sometimes the desire can do it and it is much better this way, that they come with that desire.
pero las ganas a veces lo pueden y está mucho mejor así, que vengan con esas ganas.
之后我们将有时间换装备，我们对所有来的男孩感到非常高兴。
Afterwards we will have time to change gear and we are very happy with all the boys who have come.
después para bajar un cambio ya tendremos tiempo y estamos muy contentos con todos los chicos que han venido.
莱昂内尔，你好吗？
Leonel, how are you?
Leonel, ¿cómo estás?
奥克塔维奥作为报告员在此。
Octavio here as rapporteurs.
Octavio acá de relatores.
你谈到了一些人，我想问你关于普雷斯蒂亚尼的事情。
You talked about some guys, I wanted to ask you about Prestiani.
Hablaste de algunos chicos, yo quería preguntarte por Prestiani.
你怎么看？
How do you see it?
¿Cómo lo ves?
因为那是与维尼修斯一起被全世界谈论的那一集的时间就过去了。
Because that's where the time of that episode with Vinicius that was so talked about around the world passed a little.
Porque por ahí pasó un poco el tiempo de ese episodio con Vinicius que fue tan comentado en todo el mundo.
当你看到他时，他的情绪也许有点激动，毕竟他又回到了一个男孩的状态。
there as you saw him, emotionally perhaps a little mobilized, returning to what he is, after all, a boy.
por ahí como lo viste, anímicamente quizá un poco movilizado, volviendo a esto que es un chico al fin y al cabo.
而且，如果从足球角度来看，他在 U-20 世界杯上并表现出色对您来说很重要。
And also if from a football perspective it is important to you that he was there and did a good job in the U-20 World Cup.
y también si futbolísticamente es importante para vos que él estuvo y cumplió una buena labor en el Mundial Sub-20.
正如你从精神方面的各个方面看到的那样，因为所发生的事情，特别是从足球方面。
-  -
谢谢。
As you see it in every aspect from the mental side because of what happened and especially from the football side.
como lo ves en todo aspecto desde lo mental por lo que sucedió y sobre todo desde lo futbolístico.
我们甚至不谈论发生的事情，因为我认为没有人和我可以和他谈论这个话题。
Thank you.
Gracias.
我对他的看法很好，我认为他很完美，他是一个能为我们做出贡献的男孩。
We don't even talk about what happened because I don't think there is anyone and I to talk about that topic with him.
de lo que sucedió ni hablamos porque no creo que sea nadie y yo para hablar de ese tema con él.
他甚至在右边打球，我们知道他在左边打球，这是一个很好的变化。
And I see him well, I see him perfect, he is a boy who can contribute to us.
Y lo veo bien, lo veo perfecto, es un chico que a nosotros nos puede aportar.
我们所拥有的，所以也......
He is even playing on the right, we know that he was playing on the left and it is a good variation.
Incluso está jugando por derecha, sabemos que por izquierda lo venía haciendo y es una buena variante.
我们会给他一个上场的机会，并展示他的能力。
to what we have, so also...
a lo que tenemos, así que también...
他进入 20 岁以下的事实对你来说也是一个很重要的平台，这是一个直接的前因。
We will give him a chance to play and demonstrate how valid he is.
Hagaremos chance de que pueda jugar y pueda demostrar todo lo válido que es.
嗯，是的，符合逻辑。
And the fact that he has been in the sub 20 is a platform that is also important to you, such an immediate antecedent.
Y que haya estado en el sub 20, es una plataforma también para vos importante ese antecedente tan inmediato.
第一个能够召唤它的工具是我们知道它......
The first tool to be able to summon it is that we know it...
La primera herramienta para poder convocarlo es que lo conocemos...
他有孩子们，他有巴勃罗，令人愉快的头脑，还有那些认识他的人。
He has had the boys, he has had Pablo, the pleasant head, those who know him.
ha tenido los chicos, ha tenido Pablo, el cabezón placente, los que lo conocen.
这是选择的第一个条目。
and that is the first entry to the selection.
y esa es la primera entrada a la selección.
也许另一个没有经历过青春的男孩更难。
Maybe another boy who hasn't gone through youth is more difficult.
A lo mejor otro chico que no ha pasado por juvenil es más difícil.
能够见到他，而且他很清楚这里的属性是什么，所以，是的，从逻辑上来说，他最好是从这里经过的。
to be able to meet him and he knows very well what the property is, so yes, logically, it is better that he has passed through here.
poder conocerlo y sabe muy bien lo que es el predio, así que sí, lógico, es mejor que haya pasado por acá.
莱昂内尔，你好吗？
Leonel, how are you?
Leonel, ¿qué tal?
这里，这里。
Here, here.
Acá, acá.
莱昂内尔、马克西莫·希诺兹和埃尔德里奥·克拉林。
Leonel, Máximo Hinoz and Elderio Clarín.
Leonel, Máximo Hinoz y Elderio Clarín.
回到决赛，我想问你......
Going back to the final, I wanted to ask you...
Volviendo a lo de la finalísima, quería preguntarte...
如果您在谈判可能的总部时有任何联系，最重要的是......
If you had any contact at the time of negotiating the possible headquarters and above all...
Si tuviste algún contacto en el momento de negociación de la posible sede y sobre todo...
因为来自西班牙的他们把伯纳乌作为舞台。
because from Spain they had set the Bernabéu as the stage.
porque desde España habían puesto como escenario el Bernabéu.
如果您与西班牙教练路易斯·德拉富恩特有过联系，考虑到……
If you had contact with Luis de la Fuente, the Spain coach, taking into account the...
Si tuviste contacto con Luis de la Fuente, el técnico de España, teniendo en cuenta la...
你对他的信任，如果他们开口说话，如果你这么认为……
the trust you have with him, if they spoke and if you think that...
la confianza que tenés con él, si hablaron y si crees que…
所生成的一切。
everything that was generated.
todo lo que se generó.
它可能会加剧世界杯上与西班牙发生对抗的可能性。
It can motivate a greater morbidity to a possible confrontation that occurs with Spain in the World Cup.
puede motivar a un morbo más grande a un posible enfrentamiento que se dé con España en el Mundial.
是的，我和路易斯谈过，我想是在那周的星期三。
Yes, I spoke with Luis, I think it was on Wednesday of that week.
Sí, con Luis hablé, creo que fue el día miércoles de esa semana.
另一方面，我们同意我们......
And on the other hand, we had agreed that we had...
Y por otra parte, habíamos quedado que teníamos...
我们必须一起做一些事情，但最终没有发生，因为最后的事情
We had to do some things together that in the end didn't happen because the very final
teníamos que hacer unas cosas juntos que al final después no se dio porque la finalísima
它被暂停了，我们将参加两个联合会之间的某种采访。
It was suspended and we are going to go to a kind of interview between the two federations.
Se suspendió y vamos a ir a una especie de entrevista entre las dos federaciones.
是的，我在周二或周三发表了讲话，我们讨论了有关这场比赛的一些事情，他和我一样。
And yes, I spoke on Tuesday or Wednesday and we talked about some things regarding this game and he was the same as me.
Y sí que hablé el martes o miércoles y hablamos unas cosas con respecto a este partido y él estaba igual que yo.
不知道发生了什么。
without knowing what was happening.
sin saber lo que pasaba.
而关于...
And regarding...
Y con respecto a...
最后阿根廷和西班牙永远是一场重要的比赛，
In the end Argentina and Spain will always be an important match,
Al final Argentina y España siempre serán un partido importante,
Querés Chamaleño 是阿根廷巴西人？
Querés Chamaleño was an Argentina-Brazil?
¿Querés Chamaleño fue una Argentina-Brasil?
它们本身就是重要的游戏。
They are games in themselves that are important.
Son partidos de por sí que son importantes.
我认为这没有必要发生。
I don't think it's necessary for this to have happened.
No creo que sea necesario que haya pasado esto.
不，我不这么认为，真的。
No, I don't think so, really.
No, no lo creo, la verdad.
你好，莱昂内尔，下午好。
Hello, Leonel, good afternoon.
Hola, Leonel, buenas tardes.
Adrián de Benedictis for Página 12。
Adrián de Benedictis for Página 12.
Adrián de Benedictis para Página 12.
你最想从这两场友谊赛中强调比赛的哪些方面或者你最希望得出结论？
What aspects of the game are you going to emphasize or do you most hope to draw conclusions from these two friendlies?
¿En qué aspectos del juego vas a hacer hincapié o tenés más esperanza de sacar conclusiones en estos dos amistosos?
嗯，原则上总是通过球来加强我们的美德。
Well, in principle always strengthening our virtues through the ball.
Bueno, en principio siempre fortaleciendo nuestras virtudes a través de la pelota.
我想如果我们必须...
and I think if we would have to...
y creo que si tendríamos que...
我们必须努力工作，尤其是当我们没有球的时候。
We have to work especially when we don't have the ball.
Tenemos que trabajar sobre todo en el momento de no tener la pelota.
是需要努力、继续加强还是做得不好？
Is it something to work on, to continue strengthening or if we don't do it well?
¿Es algo para trabajarlo, para seguir fortaleciendo o si no lo hacemos bien?
尝试改进它，这就是我们这些天一直在努力的事情。
try to improve it and that is what we have been working on these days.
intentar mejorarlo y en eso hemos trabajado estos días.
在进攻方面，加强球队的工作。
and in terms of attack, strengthen what the team does.
y en cuanto al ataque fortalecer lo que hace el equipo.
最后，当你每隔 X 次见面时，选择是非常困难的。
In the end it is very difficult in a selection when you meet every X amount of time.
Al final es muy difícil en una selección cuando te encontrás cada X tiempo.
想要改变一些本来很好的事情...
Wanting to change something that had been good...
Querer cambiar algo que venía siendo bien...
抽时间是非常困难的，我们花了很多时间去玩。
It is very difficult to take time, it took us a lot of time to play.
Es muy difícil llevar un tiempo, a nosotros nos llevó un montón de tiempo jugar.
还好，不知道要多久。
Fairly well, I don't know how long.
medianamente bien, no sé cuánto tiempo.
现在，距世界杯还有两三个月，也许我们想改变我们的比赛方式。
and now, two or three months before the World Cup, maybe we want to change our way of playing.
y ahora a dos o tres meses del Mundial a lo mejor queremos cambiar nuestra manera de jugar.
也许我们做对了，但我认为我们更倾向于做错而不是做对。
Maybe we get it right, but I think we are more on the side of not getting it right than getting it right.
A lo mejor acertamos, pero yo creo que estamos más para el lado de no acertar que acertar.
加强一点，当我们无球或无球时采取合理的预防措施
strengthen that a little and take precautions logically when we don't have the ball or when
un poco fortalecer eso y tomar recaudo lógicamente cuando no tenemos la pelota o cuando se
失去，这些是我认为我们必须努力的事情，而且我们这些天一直在努力。
-  -
你好吗？
lose, those are the things that I imagine we have to work on and we have been working on these days.
pierda, esas son las cosas que imagino que tenemos que trabajar y hemos estado en estos días trabajando.
也适用于 atingoles。
How are you doing?
¿Cómo está?
自 2018 年整个故事开始以来，您已经浏览过很多清单。
and also for the atingoles.
y también para el atingoles.
有很多清单，而且是决定性的清单。
You've been through a lot of lists since this whole story started in 2018.
Has pasado con muchas listas desde que arrancó toda esta historia en 2018.
最重要的也许是卡塔尔，但您将这份最终名单放在哪里？
There were many lists, decisive lists.
Fueron muchas listas, listas decisivas.
定位是最重要的，如果这比足球运动员每次被排除在外时更难说的话。
The most perhaps most important was Qatar, but where do you position this final list?
la más quizás más importante fue la de Qatar, pero ¿dónde posicionas esta lista final?
这是最重要的，因为它即将到来。
positioning and the most important of all and if it is more difficult to say than for a footballer when he is left out, every time time passes.
la posicionarse y la más importante de todas y si cuesta más decirle que en un futbolista cuando se queda fuera, cada vez que pasa el tiempo.
毫无疑问，卡塔尔是我的第一个国家队，因为当教练时
It is the most important because it is the one that is coming.
Es la más importante porque es la que viene.
除了两次获得美洲杯帆船赛冠军之外，之前……不，是两次，之前。
Without a doubt, Qatar was my first and because when a coach
Sin duda que la de Qatar fue mi primera y porque cuando un entrenador
有这样的经验，但由于给出一个亲世界的名单是不一样的，
Beyond having had two America's Cups, before... No, two, before it took.
más allá de que haya tenido dos Copas Américas, antes que... No, dos, antes de que tardó.
经历了很多曲折，我想事情就是这样。
There is that experience, but since giving a pro-world list is not the same,
Está esa experiencia, pero como dar una lista pro mundial no es lo mismo,
确实如此，除此之外它还有众所周知的困难。
a lot of twists and turns and I think that's how it is.
un montón de vueltas y yo creo que es así.
以及最后男孩的伤亡。
It was, apart from that it had its difficulties as everyone knows.
fue, aparte que tuvo sus dificultades como todos saben.
但这个，由于距离很近，人们会忘记它并接受它......
with the casualties of the final boys.
con las bajas de los chicos finales.
以不同的方式和优秀的足球运动员
but this one, given the proximity, one forgets about it and takes it...
pero esta, dada la proximidad, uno se hace olvido de esa y la toma...
很难告诉他他不会参加世界杯。
in a different way and the good footballer
de una manera diferente y el futbolista bueno
原则上，在我们给出名单的那天，我们会去看名单，然后打电话给球员告诉他们“不”。
In principle, the day we give the list, we go to the list and we are going to call the players to tell them no.
En principio, nosotros el día que demos la lista, vamos a la lista y nos vamos a llamar a los jugadores para decirles que no.
我不认为这是...
I don't think it's...
No creo que sea...
公平一点，然后我们就会给出清单。
Let it be fair, then well, we will give the list.
que sea justo, entonces bueno, daremos la lista.
考虑对球队最好的事情，并知道一名球员被排除在世界杯之外是多么痛苦。
thinking about the best for the team and knowing how painful it is for a player to be left out of a World Cup.
pensando en lo mejor para el equipo y sabiendo lo doloroso que es para un jugador quedarse afuera de un Mundial.
迭戈，你好吗？
Diego, how are you?
Diego, ¿cómo estás?
这里是 Melissa Cardoso 为 Radio Tuit、Vaca Muerta 为 Uquén 以及 Latinizados 服务。
Here Melissa Cardoso for Radio Tuit, Vaca Muerta in Uquén and for Latinizados.
Acá Melissa Cardoso para Radio Tuit, Vaca Muerta en Uquén y para Latinizados.
首先，作为一名优秀的内乌肯人，我忍不住想问你一个问题……
First, as a good Neuquen, I can't help but ask you about...
Primero, como buen neuquino, no puedo evitar preguntarte por...
正如您所看到的，它是如何运作的，如果这些可能的 26 个或这些初始草案适合的话。
As you see it, how it has been working, if these possible 26 or these initial drafts fit.
como lo veis, como viene trabajando, si encajan estos posibles 26 o estos borradores iniciales.
然后问问自己，对于《糖果盒》中的这次告别或双重告别有何感受，您也将如何经历？
and then ask yourself how you feel about this farewell or double farewell in La Bombonera, how are you going to experience it too?
y después preguntarte cómo te sentís vos con esta despedida o doble despedida en La Bombonera, ¿cómo lo vas a vivir también?
马科斯又上场了。
Marcos has played again.
Marcos ha vuelto a jugar.
他有这样的能力，让我们看看这个词是否会被传出来，幸运的是我们认识他，这就是为什么
He has that, let's see if the word comes out, that luck that we know him and that's why
tiene esa, a ver si me sale la palabra, esa suerte de que lo conocemos y por eso
电话已经打赢了。
The call has been won.
se ha ganado la convocatoria.
它刚刚回来，我们相信它将继续呈上升趋势。
which is just coming back and we believe that it will go on an upward trend.
que recién está volviendo y creemos que va a ir en línea ascendente.
这就是我们打电话的原因。
and that's why the call.
y por eso la convocatoria.
好吧，这是一个
and well that is a
y bueno eso es un
这是一个给予我们很多的男孩的宠爱。
It is a pampering of a boy who has given us a lot.
Es un mimo a un chico que nos ha dado un montón.
他可以给我们，无论如何，我们相信加布里埃尔·罗哈斯也可以给我们。
that he can give us, in any case there is also Gabriel Rojas who we believe can give us.
que nos puede dar, en cualquier caso también está Gabriel Rojas que creemos que nos puede aportar.
并在那里推动并利用你所拥有的时间
and be there to push and use the minutes you have
y estar ahí para presionar y utilizar los minutos que tenga
看看是否适合。
to see if it can fit.
para ver si se puede meter.
我也希望人们能够享受它。
I also want people to enjoy it.
Yo también estoy con ganas de que la gente disfrute.
最后我是板凳上的球迷。
In the end I am a fan on the bench.
Yo al final soy un hincha puesto en el banco de suplentes.
同样的事情，同样的事情，我来到那里，我给出了一些指示，我喜欢见到球员，不认为这有什么不同，我总是说同样的事情。
Same thing, same thing, I come there, I give a couple of instructions and I enjoy seeing the players, don't think it's very different, I always said the same thing.
Lo mismo, igual, vengo ahí, doy un par de indicaciones y disfruto viendo a los jugadores, no se crean que es muy diferente, siempre dije lo mismo.
当有可能在主场打两场比赛时，那就很好了。
and when there is the possibility of playing two games at home, it is good.
y cuando está la posibilidad de jugar dos partidos en tu casa, está bueno.
我们和你们一样享受它。
and we enjoyed it just like all of you.
y lo disfrutamos igual que todos ustedes.
最后一个问题请。
Last question please.
Última pregunta por favor.
大家下午好。
Good afternoon everyone.
Buenas tardes a todos.
下午好，教练。
Good afternoon, coach.
Buenas tardes, coach.
我要用英语问我的问题。
I'm going to ask my question in English.
Voy a preguntar mi pregunta en inglés.
好的，我来翻译一下。
Ok, I'll translate.
Ok, traduciré.
莫里塔尼亚将是你的下一个对手。
Moritania will be your next opponent.
Moritania será tu siguiente oponente.
您对毛里塔尼亚了解多少？
What do you know about Mauritania?
¿Qué sabe de Mauritania?
您预计对阵毛里塔尼亚国家队的比赛会是什么样的？
What type of game do you expect against the Mauritania national team?
¿Cuál tipo de juego esperas contra el equipo nacional de Mauritania?
不，但我想我明白了，我想我明白了，这很英语……
No, but I think I understood, I think I understood, it's quite English...
No, pero creo que entendí, creo que entendí, es un inglés bastante...
可以说是可以忍受的
bearable let's say
llevadero digamos
不，不，但我想我理解得很好。
No, no, but I think I understood, very well.
No, no, pero creo que he entendido, muy bien.
他们在那里？
-  -
你怎么说？
让我们来看看。
Where are they there?
¿Ahí dónde están?
原则上，事实是我们不...
How do you say?
¿Cómo se dice?
我们喜欢与充满热情的对手一起比赛，因为最终
Let's see.
A ver.
当然，他们带着巨大的热情而来，这种热情，我以前几天的男孩们为例，
Surely they come with enormous enthusiasm and that enthusiasm, I gave the boys from the other day as an example,
seguramente vengan con una ilusión enorme y esa ilusión, yo les ponía de ejemplo a los chicos del otro día,
除了思考我们的对手是谁之外，我们还必须……
that beyond thinking about who we play against, we have to be...
que más allá de pensar contra quién jugamos, nosotros tenemos que estar...
100% 实现我们的目标，即...
100% with our goal which is...
100% con nuestro objetivo que es...
作为一个团队聚集在一起，作为一个团队提高，因为如果我们认为毛里塔尼亚会很容易。
get together as a team, improve as a team, because if we think that Mauritania is going to be easy.
juntarnos como equipo, mejorar como equipo, porque si pensamos que Mauritania va a ser fácil.
我们与阿拉伯国家队一起开始了世界杯，我们不再认为理论上这是国家队。
We started the World Cup with Arabia and we lost thinking it was theoretically the national team.
Empezamos el mundial con Arabia y perdimos pensando que era la selección teóricamente.
没有容易的对手，这是一支球队，作为一支球队，有全国最好的球队，据我们所知，他们已经国有化
There is no easy rival, it is a team and as a team there are the best in the country and from what we know they have nationalized
No hay rival fácil, es una selección y como selección están los mejores del país y por lo que sabemos han nacionalizado
好吧，好吧，我们也做到了，问题是......
Well, okay, we've done it too, the thing is...
Bueno, está bien, nosotros también lo hemos hecho, lo que pasa es que...
我们是本地人，所以我认为这造成了困难。
Ours are native, so I think that makes the difficulty.
los nuestros son autóctonos, entonces yo creo que eso hace la dificultad.
很高兴能够与愿意全力以赴的对手比赛。
and happy to be able to play against an opponent who is going to give their all.
y contento de poder jugar contra un rival que va a dar el máximo.
他们不会来这里说，我们来看糖果吧，不，他们会来，正如先生所说的，全力以赴。
and they are not going to come here and say, we come to see the candy bar, no, they are going to come, as the mister said, to give their all.
y no va a venir acá a decir, venimos a conocer la bombonera, no, van a venir, como dijo el mister, a dar el máximo.
这很好，非常感谢您能够
and that's good so thank you for being able to
y eso está bueno así que agradecerle poder
玩，因为最终我们实现这一目标并不容易，而且它的倾向已经
play because in the end it has not been easy for us to achieve and the predisposition for it has been
jugar porque al final no ha estado fácil tampoco para nosotros poder conseguir y la predisposición de ello ha estado
非常好，我们很高兴。
very good and we are happy.
muy buena y estamos contentos.
谢谢教练，谢谢大家，下午好。
-  -
谢谢。
Thank you coach, thank you all, good afternoon.
Gracias entrenador, gracias a todos, buenas tardes.